=The Road to Splendor=
(Adapted from China Literature author Zhizhi's novel of the same name)
=Episode 10=
Now that the Yan family has fallen,
Madam Yu has been bedridden ever since.
Could it be that she not only failed to earn merit,
But is also being blamed?
A smart woman like Madam Yu
Surely would not.
You're overthinking it.
I heard something, though.
Her daughter-in-law
Stirred up a huge mess.
Really?
I heard that too.
See?
Trying to win favor with the imperial court
Is no easy thing.
One misstep and the whole game is lost.
I doubt the Yu family will recover
Anytime soon.
Alright. Let's just play.
(20,000 taels; 5,000 taels. 20 shops: 30,000 taels.)
(Cash: 42,000 taels. Grand total: 97,000 taels.)
The accounts don't match.
(Annual Accounts of the Xie Family)
Zhao Ling.
Come in.
Didn't I tell you
To hand over all of Jiuweijiao's assets?
Why is three thousand taels missing?
If you want to clear the accounts,
You must hand over everything.
Why be greedy for such a small gain?
You gave up a hundred thousand taels.
What's three thousand?
Aren't you going back to the capital, Miss Xie?
Why do you still bother with this?
From now on,
Just take good care of yourself.
My affairs
Are none of your concern.
None of my concern?
These three thousand taels
Are enough to get you executed.
All right.
I only did this for your own good.
Yet you think I meddle too much.
I
Must have
Overestimated my importance.
Let's hope you can keep it hidden.
If you leave loose ends now
And trouble arises later,
This will all be evidence for confiscating your property.
Miss Xie.
Are we really going back to the capital?
Can you bear to leave Mr. Zhao?
(Xie Residence)
Miss Xie.
For your help in the case, His Highness
Has sent me to invite you to claim your reward.
I am grateful for His Highness's favor.
Actually,
There's one more favor to ask.
His Highness truly values Zhao Ling.
He wants you to advise him.
Joining the army is just an excuse.
The main purpose
Is to change his identity.
After a few years of training,
He'll be moved to the capital.
With His Highness's favor,
He will have a bright future.
He was chosen by the Sixteenth Master himself.
What do you call that?
That's called a trusted aide.
I understand.
Alright.
I'll take my leave.
(A thousand taels)
(You gave up a hundred thousand taels.)
(What's three thousand?)
(The world is wide.)
(I wish you well.)
You haven't left?
I thought...
Thought what?
You thought
I'd be back in the capital.
Wasn't the Sixteenth Master going to reward you?
Miss Xie, you did well in the salt case.
Is there anything you desire?
I wish to have a proper identity.
A household register under the name of Xie Tingyun.
My family fell from grace.
I barely escaped with my life.
My household was struck off the rolls.
To walk in this world,
I need that document.
True.
You and Zhao Ling share deep feelings.
You'll need that document
To marry with proper ceremony.
(Household Register)
This is the reward I want.
Mr. Zhao, will you marry me?
Though I was born into a noble family,
I now have nothing.
Thank you for your kindness,
For putting three thousand taels in my bundle.
Now,
I want to use those silver notes
As my betrothal gift.
Betrothal gift?
Mr. Zhao,
Will you marry me?
I don't want to part from you.
I like the name Xie Tingyun.
I like you and Sen,
And Biao and Chuan too.
They are all good people.
I've packed my things.
I want to join the army with all of you.
You like me
And Sen?
What does Sen have to do with it?
I want to walk this road
With all of you.
Together we'll do business,
Together we'll earn our fame.
Start from nothing,
And build a legacy.
We'll earn
A real place in this world.
I'll marry you.
So you're investing in the venture?
Did the Sixteenth Master send you to persuade me
To join the army?
Mr. Zhao,
Joining the army may be your only chance
To improve your standing.
You were cast out of your family at eight.
You've struggled through hardship all these years.
But in the end,
You remain a lowly merchant.
Times are good for you now,
But what happens when the Sixteenth Master leaves?
What about years from now?
Without changing your status,
You will forever be
Fish on the chopping block,
At the mercy of others.
For you,
Marriage
Is nothing but a bond of interests
And a path to advance your standing?
The sugar is sweet,
While coptis root is bitter.
Boiled together, they make a sweet healing draught.
Perhaps in this world,
The strongest alliances are forged
When sincere hearts yield mutual benefit,
And that benefit
Ripens into genuine affection.
The two can barely be told apart.
Just like you and me.
Bound by shared interests,
We may rely on each other fully.
I know my proposal is abrupt.
It may offend you.
So
I'll only ask this once.
No need to answer right away.
Please think it over.
(Yu Residence)
Even if it's not the grand affair we were promised,
It should at least match a family of this stature.
But now,
The procession is shabby, and barely any guests.
(Guest List) Madam is giving you the cold shoulder.
You should call me Madam Fan now.
Understood.
I've married into the Yu family after all.
That's what I wanted.
As long as my husband cares for me,
He will stand up for me.
I refuse to believe
That I'm not on an upward path.
The days ahead are still long.
It's not that I'm harsh on Fan.
I'm just afraid you've been blinded
By temporary affection.
She is indeed talented.
But her actions
Nearly brought the Yu family
To the brink of ruin.
Fu Tingyun used the flower cakes to blackmail me
For Fan's written confession.
With that confession in hand,
Fan's fate
Will forever be in her grip.
If we ever clash in the future,
We'll already be at a disadvantage.
The Huaying affair
Was Zuo Junjie's doing.
Fan gave false testimony,
But she wasn't
The ringleader.
I'm glad to see you're loyal and honorable.
Since you're set on this,
I wish you and your wife harmony.
If I say any more,
It would seem like I'm sowing discord.
Mother.
(Commentaries on the Four Books) The annotated edition by Master Fan
Is a classic text that deserves to be passed down through the ages.
It should have been treasured.
Yet Fan
Treated it
Like something to be pawned or traded away.
I've already bought back all those texts.
Return them to her.
I hope she'll be grateful to you.
What I can do
Ends here.
She actually sold the classics?
For what?
Money?
The marriage is settled.
As for other things,
Don't dwell on them.
For the family matter,
I was fortunate to have some standing with the Crown Prince,
And I've managed to smooth things over.
Jingxiu,
From now on,
You must not act so willfully again.
I understand, Mother.
Leave now.
Madam.
Send a letter to Madam Zuo.
Tell her
That an old acquaintance is coming to find her.
A widow being bullied by others
Is truly pitiful.
If she needs our help,
She can let us know.
Understood.
I'll go right away.
(I thought she was as elegant and pure as a narcissus.)
(Unlike other women consumed by worldly things.)
(But she casually sells off treasured texts,)
(with no regard for their value.)
(The name Yake,) [*Meaning a cultured person.]
(does she truly deserve it?)
Jingxiu.
It's getting late.
Let's retire for the night.
What did Miss Xie ask you?
She said
She wanted to marry me.
She said she wanted me to marry her.
And did you agree?
She already gave the betrothal gift.
Three thousand taels.
Actual silver, handed over just like that?
This is a lifelong commitment.
You'd better think it through.
But she doesn't really want to marry me.
She just wants to do business with me.
For a couple to live together,
The most important thing
Is sincerity.
Whether it's sincerity or business,
We must first secure a future for the brothers.
I even dared to be a salt bandit.
What's there to fear
In getting married?
Pack your things.
We're going to join the army.
Join the army?
Great!
Then I can learn martial arts!
Wait.
Why join the army all of a sudden?
Am I going too?
Have you settled on a place?
Ganlin Town.
I also serve in Ganlin Town.
Buddy,
You didn't choose it just because you miss me,
Did you?
Miss Xie,
Are you going too?
Since we've got a new household register,
I'll go too.
Alright.
Since you refused my wedding gift,
I will grant you one hundred mu of land
As a wedding gift.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Miss Xie, you have a sharp mind.
Miss Xie, you are quite astute.
The road ahead is long.
Be cautious at every step.
I will always bear
Your teachings in mind.
When you reach Ganlin Town,
Make sure to work hard.
When you are promoted to battalion commander,
Later,
You will be very useful to me.
I will not disappoint Your Highness.
(Xie Residence)
It's time to send a letter
To Mother.
(Dear Mother,)
(when you read this,)
(I have taken the surname Xie.)
(And I am engaged to Zhao Ling.)
(After all the upheavals,)
(I have come to see that a woman's marriage)
(should not be based only on status or wealth.)
(Character and integrity matter more.)
(Zhao Ling may come from a humble background,)
(but he is loyal, honorable,)
(brave and resourceful.)
(Now,)
(he has found an opportunity.)
(He will join the army in Ganlin Town.)
(He has great potential.)
(I am willing to stand by his side.)
(We will start from nothing.)
(I believe that with his sense of duty,)
(and with my planning,)
(we will surely carve out a future.)
(I cannot be by your side to care for you,)
(so please take good care of yourself.)
(Your daughter,)
(Tingyun.)
Biao
And Chuan.
You're back.
You scared me just now.
What are you doing?
Don't come near.
Time to tickle you.
No tickling!
You're getting cheeky again.
I was wrong.
Don't tickle me.
Strong liquor burns the throat.
Let's have fruit syrup instead.
Here.
In this world, kinship
Need not come from birth.
When hearts are one,
Even strangers
Can walk the same path.
No matter how hard the road ahead,
I want to build a family with you.
A family of our own.
Gather the good.
Trust one another with our lives.
Alright.
I will never let
Your kindness go unanswered.
People say that wealth
Blinds the eyes.
But these worldly riches
Truly do not interest me.
All my planning and scheming
Is only to do what others cannot do,
And to bring down those others cannot.
Lord Yan has been arrested,
And Grand Secretary Liu is implicated.
In court rivalries,
If those above do not fall,
How can those below rise?
With the Liu family's fall,
A seat opens in the Grand Secretariat.
If Master enters the Grand Secretariat,
We will hear by year's end.
You have accomplished such a great deed,
And Master will surely be grateful.
We also owe thanks to Fan
For making that mistake before the Crown Prince.
After this,
Who will still be on guard against our family?
Others will only think
That the Yu family was too eager
To curry favor with His Highness.
But they do not know
That true success
Need not be seen by others.
Indeed.
Did not Madam Yan fail
Because she was too conspicuous?
And also because
She and her husband were not of one mind.
Do I look good?
Good.
Miss Xie,
This is my husband.
Zheng San.
We were separated in the famine,
And have just reunited.
Thank you for taking us in.
My wife and I
Will serve you faithfully.
We will not betray your trust.
We've shared life and death together.
From now on, we'll stand by each other.
Chuan's not hungry. Don't give him any.
You rascal.
Smells good, right?
- Careful, don't burn yourself. - Here.
It's fine.
Smells really good.
Careful, don't burn yourself.
Mr. Zhao!
Pry out the root.
Mother, take it slow.
I told you not to come out.
Mother, slow down.
Mr. Zhao.
Be careful.
Mr. Zhao, please take this.
Wish you luck and safety.
Thank you.
Hold firmly.
Here.
Thank you.
Ganlin is far away.
Hold firmly.
Safe travels.
Yucheng.
Will you come with me
To seek a post in Ganlin?
My mother is old.
I...
Come with us, Yucheng.
Come on.
Right.
Go for it.
Following Mr. Zhao
Is better than being a bandit or smuggling salt.
If you're willing,
Once we're settled,
We can bring your mother
To join us.
Yucheng, you have real skill.
You'll have a place in the army.
Your mother will be at peace too.
I, Yang Yucheng,
Shall obey your wishes.
I will follow Mr. Zhao to Ganlin.
I will not go back on my word.
Rise.
Good!
This is good.
When I'm free...
Mr. Zhao.
The flowers Miss Xie likes,
I've dug them up.
What about you?
You'll stay in Yongning Prefecture.
I've secured a salt permit for you
From the Sixteenth Master.
What you make of it
Is up to you.
(Salt Permit)
Mr. Zhao.
Money and supplies are no problem.
But the salt permit is the hardest to get.
Mr. Zhao,
When you leave for Ganlin,
Leave the salt business to me.
We'll remain
As we were.
No matter how big the business grows,
It all comes from you, Mr. Zhao.
(Outskirts)
Ninth Young Lady.
On your way to Ganlin,
Take care of yourself.
Thank you for your concern, Madam.
From now on,
I will start from nothing with Mr. Zhao.
It will be a fresh start.
These two have talent,
And they have strategy,
And they have luck.
But in the end,
They are still inexperienced.
They truly believe
That starting from nothing is easy.
Little do they know that climbing up from the bottom
Is not about the obvious enemies
Who sit high above.
It's the small potato.
One wrong move,
And you'll be rolling in the mud with lowlifes.
Look at the things they're carrying.
Too exquisite.
Isn't this exactly the mistake that Madam Yan made?
(Yongning Prefecture)
(Admonitions for Women Hall)
The rule here has always been for skirts to cover the feet.
Yet you dared to cut yours short by three cun.
It's the harvest season,
And my elder brother is gravely ill.
I thought that with a shorter skirt,
I could work in the fields more easily.
First,
Your brother is ill,
And his wife can tend to him.
You have no part in that.
Second,
You are an unmarried young woman.
Yet you show yourself in public to do farm work.
You are shaming
Your future husband's reputation.
Third,
Do you not know that these three cun of exposed skin
Could ruin the reputation of many families?
Ms. Zuo,
A letter has arrived from Yongning Prefecture.
We're here.
(Ganlin Town) We're here.
We've arrived in Ganlin Town.
(Ganlin Town)
I need to register at the yamen first.
You all follow General Mo to get settled.
General!
General.
What are you doing here?
I asked everyone I met
When you would return.
But no one would tell me.
I wanted to ask Madam,
But I was afraid of getting scolded.
So I just waited here.
After several days,
I finally waited for your return.
You poor thing.
Where is Madam?
The wife of Commander Wang
Is here to welcome the new soldiers' families.
Right now, Madam
Is inside with Madam Wang.
Oh no.
Here.
General.
Sanniang.
I want to talk to Miss Xie.
Miss Xie.
General Mo.
Let me introduce you.
She is
My...
The woman at home.
Greetings, Madam Mo.
No.
Miss Xie,
You don't need to call her Madam.
Just call her Lu.
This is Miss Xie.
(Concubine Lu, General Mo's concubine) Miss Xie.
May I ask a favor?
Could you take her
With you in your carriage?
Please don't let her get off.
Sorry to trouble you.
Get in the carriage.
General.
Get in.
Be good.
Get in now.
Sorry to trouble you, Miss Xie.
You were
Brought here by the general too?
Then from now on,
Treat me with due respect.
He sure
Spends a lot on you.
I heard supplies are tight in Ganlin Town.
General Mo told us to stock up.
So I bought a little bit of everything.
He also lets you hold all the money?
He says he's not good at managing things.
He asked me to help him handle it.
That ungrateful man.
Let me be clear
Right from the start.
In a household like ours,
Rules matter most.
The two of you
Haven't gone through proper formalities.
As the newcomer,
You must defer to me
In all things.
Do not overstep.
Do you understand?
Well,
I really don't quite understand.
Miss Xie.
Several military wives have come.
They say they've come to welcome you.
There's Madam Wang from the Commander's residence,
And Madam Mo.
I wonder who she is.
That girl is really lovely.
Here she comes.
She's so pretty.
Greetings, ladies.
Look.
(Madam Mo, General Mo's wife) You are truly
(Madam Wang, Commander Wang's wife) like someone out of a painting.
We've been traveling and are quite worn out.
I hope we haven't disturbed you.
Don't be so formal.
From now on,
We're all family.
Come.
This is Madam Wang.
And
This is Xie from Yongning Prefecture.
So beautiful.
Xie, you are truly lovely.
We've only just arrived.
There are just small tokens of our appreciation.
Madam Wang and Madam Mo, I hope you will not mind.
Not at all.
Come.
How exquisite.
You go first.
So pretty.
I'll take this one.
Lovely.
Pink.
Pretty.
Very pretty.
Isn't it?
Pink looks lovely.
She's new,
Yet she shows off.
Why can't I?
So beautiful.
Is it pretty?
Pretty.
Madam Mo, it's beautiful.
From now on,
No more "Madam".
Let's treat each other
Like sisters.
So pretty.
We military wives are simple folks.
We rarely have a chance to dress up.
In the whole garrison, there's just one person
Who's always so flashy.
She even picks wildflowers just to dress up.
Where are my flowers?
Miss Xie,
Come take a look.
Could your luggage have been robbed?
Where did you steal those velvet flowers
And stick them all over your head?
You tactless fool.
She's a distinguished guest here with her fiance to join the army.
She's truly from a military household.
If you damage her things,
You'll have to pay.
Exactly.
You have misunderstood.
I lent her these velvet flowers just to try on.
Exactly.
Miss Xie is generous.
Unlike some people
Who are petty.
- You! - Who are you talking about?
Say that again!
Should've said they were her castoffs.
Why give them to me then?
If she's worn
This velvet flower,
I don't want it.
Let's go.
(Gandu Circuit Military Camp)
Look.
Where did that fool come from?
He's been waiting there for four hours.
Commander.
They say a hundred years ago,
General Zhou fought the Wangur people.
With a Humu-wood tiger-sinew bow,
(Lord Wang, Gandu Circuit Commander) he slew their leader.
Today, that divine bow
Is right before your eyes.
As the saying goes,
A fine sword is gifted to a hero.
I believe
This divine bow
Is a perfect match for you, Lord Wang.
I cannot accept it.
(Li Mao, Gandu Circuit Military Advisor) You have managed the military supplies
And provisions all these years.
Your service alone is a great favor.
If you truly wish to show appreciation,
When new recruits arrive in a few days,
Just allocate more provisions for them.
Have I ever shortchanged
The soldiers' provisions?
Zhao,
Why are you standing out here?
Lord Wang.
Greetings, Lord Wang.
You're finally back.
You deserve top credit for this battle.
You should be rewarded.
I was rewarded before I returned.
There's more?
Yes.
This bow
Should be given
To the soldiers who proved themselves.
What do you think, Advisor Li?
Lord Wang, you treat your men like family.
I admire that deeply.
Lord Wang,
This is indeed a fine bow.
But on my trip to Yongning Prefecture,
I wasn't the top contributor.
Let me introduce someone to you.
Over there.
His name is Zhao Ling.
He's our new Banner Commander.
(Visiting Card)
You.
I am the Banner Commander, Zhao Ling.
Greetings, Lord Wang,
Advisor Li.
This visiting card of yours
Comes from quite a source.
Ganlin Town is just a small place.
Can you really settle for it?
I will
Stand tall
Between heaven and earth.
Lord Wang,
The bow...
Guards,
Take this bow
And
Send it to General Mo's residence.
Understood.
Drink up.
Come on.
Cheers.
Come.
Advisor Li, join us.
Zhao, come on.
Fill them up.
Bottoms up.
Alright.
Come on.
Drink up.
Three bowls in a row.
Alright.
Another round.
Come.
Fill it up.
Come, pour me another.
One more.
(Next Episode)
Miss Xie,
The fields granted by the Sixteenth Master were taken.
And now you've seized
Banner Commander Zhao's fields.
How can I face anyone
In the military now?
His fields?
I reclaimed the wasteland!
If we can't even keep a field,
How can we
Stand firm here?
If you want to fight,
Then fight.
You were absent without leave,
Abandoning your post.
By military law,
That's eighty strokes.
You have no regard for military law.
Without severe punishment,
How can discipline be maintained?
Strike!
♪The past brushes by like a falling leaf♪
♪So light, yet my steps still pause for you♪
♪Through every rise and fall, our memories remain without regret♪
♪Carved into the rings of time♪
♪How I wish I could stay a little longer, but I can't♪
♪I turn away, afraid goodbye will fill my eyes with tears♪
♪Etched deep within my heart, yet buried without a word♪
♪The warmth of your hand in mine♪
♪Still makes us want to believe♪
♪One promise for a lifetime, echoing long after we part♪
♪For one fleeting moment, I found you in the crowd♪
♪Without a word, you lit up half my life♪
♪In silence, a love too deep for words♪
♪Kept close within my heart♪
♪From now on, no one else is worth waiting for♪
♪I turn away, afraid no one will ever come home to me again♪
♪If we can build our future together, no storm can chill my heart♪
♪The warmth of your hand in mine♪
♪Still makes us want to believe♪
♪One promise for a lifetime, echoing long after we part♪